bentley.com 2010-12-03

# Bentley Web Properties Privacy Policy

Last Revised: April 22, 2008

At Bentley Systems, Incorporated, we take our users' privacy very seriously and are committed to protecting it. Therefore, we want to provide you with explicit information regarding how we collect, gather, and identify information during your visit to this site. Please read the information below about Bentley Web Properties and services that you may use. This information may be expanded or updated as we develop or change Bentley Web Properties. So that you may always know what information we collect, how we use it, and when and how we disclose it. We recommend that you review this policy from time to time to see if it has changed. Your continued use of Bentley Web Properties signifies your acceptance of our privacy policy. 

Note that this Privacy Policy applies to data collected by Bentley Web Properties and online and offline services. It does not apply to sites, services, and products that do not display or link to this statement or that have their own privacy statements. 

* * *

## Collection of Your Personal Information

To access some Bentley Web Property services, you will be asked to sign in with an e-mail address and password, which we refer to as your "credentials." By signing in on one Bentley Web Property or service, you may be automatically signed into another Bentley Web Property or service. If you access Bentley Web Property services via a mobile phone, you may also use your telephone number and a PIN as an alternative credential to your username and password. As part of creating your credentials, you may also be requested to provide questions and secret answers, which we use to help verify your identity and assist in resetting your password, as well as an alternate email address. Some services may require added security, and in these cases, you may be asked to create an additional security key. Finally, a unique ID number will be assigned to your credentials which will be used to identify your credentials and associated information. 

On some Bentley Web Properties, we ask you to provide personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address, or telephone number. We may also collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and similar things. If you choose to make a purchase or sign up for a paid subscription service, we will ask for additional information, such as your credit card number and billing address to create a Bentley Web Property billing account. 

We may collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions taken in connection with Bentley Web Properties and services. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times, and referring website addresses. 

When you receive newsletters or promotional e-mail from Bentley Web Properties, we may use Web beacons (described [below](http://www.bentley.com/web_beacons)), customized links, or similar technologies to determine whether the e-mail has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you more focused e-mail communications or other information in the future. 

In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with Bentley Web Properties, information collected through one Bentley Web Property service may be combined with information obtained through other Bentley Web Property services. We may also supplement the information we collect with information obtained from other companies. For example, we may use services from other companies that enable us to derive a general geographic area based on your IP address in order to customize certain services delivered to you based on your geographic area. 

## Use of Your Personal Information

Bentley Web Properties collects and uses your personal information to operate and improve its sites, and deliver the services or carry out the transactions you have requested. These uses may include providing you with more effective customer service; making the sites or services easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information; performing research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services, and technologies; and displaying content and advertising that are customized to your interests and preferences. 

We also use your personal information to communicate with you. We may send certain mandatory service communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, information on technical service issues, and security announcements. Some Bentley Web Property services may send periodic member letters that are considered part of the service. We may also occasionally send you product surveys or promotional mailings to inform you of other products or services available from Bentley Web Properties and its affiliates. 

Personal information collected on Bentley Web Properties and services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Bentley or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or agents maintain facilities, and by using a Bentley Web Property or service, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Bentley abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. 

## Sharing of Your Personal Information

Except as described in this statement, we will not disclose your personal information outside of Bentley and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your consent. Some Bentley Web Properties allow you to choose to share your personal information with select Bentley Web Property partners so that they can contact you about their products, services, or offers. Other sites do not share your contact information with third parties for marketing purposes, but instead may give you a choice as to whether you wish to receive communications from Bentley on behalf of external business partners about a partner's particular offering (without transferring your personal information to the third party). See the [Communication Preferences](http://www.bentley.com/BentleyWebSite/Templates/Corporate_Generic.aspx?NRMODE=Published&NRNODEGUID=%7bBFDF0ACE-0F9D-4989-B2FF-39F066686CFD%7d&NRORIGINALURL=%2fen-US%2fCorporate%2fPrivacy%2bPolicy%2ehtm&NRCACHEHINT=Guest#) section below for more information. 

Some Bentley Web Property services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such services, both Bentley and the other company may receive information collected in connection with the co-branded services. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing user or customer support, hosting websites, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose. 

We may access and/or disclose your personal information if we believe such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or legal process served on Bentley; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Bentley (including the enforcement of our agreements); or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Bentley Web Property services or members of the public. 

## Accessing Your Personal Information

You may have the ability to view or edit your personal information online. To help prevent your personal information from being viewed by others, you will be required to sign in with your credentials (e.g. username and password). The appropriate method(s) for accessing your personal information will depend on which sites or services you have used. Some Bentley Web Properties or services may collect personal information that you may be able to access through alternative means of access described by the service. Or you can use our [contact us](mailto:http://www.bentley.com/bentleywebsite/tools/sales_contact.aspx) form and we will contact you within 30 days regarding your request. 

## Communication Preferences

You can stop the delivery of future promotional e-mail from Bentley Web Properties and services by following the specific instructions set forth in such promotional e-mail. You may also have the option of proactively making choices about the communications you receive from particular Bentley Web Properties or services by [contacting us](mailto:http://www.bentley.com/bentleywebsite/tools/sales_contact.aspx). 

We may send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service issues, product surveys, new feature announcements, or news about our products and services. These communications are considered essential to the provision of the service you have requested. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered a part of the service you have chosen. 

## Security of Your Personal Information

Bentley is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always choose to log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. 

## Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information

Many Bentley Web Properties and services are intended for general audiences and do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. When a Bentley Web Property does collect age information, and users identify themselves as under 13, the site will either block such users from providing personal information, or will seek to obtain consent from parents for the collection, use and sharing of their children's personal information. We will not knowingly ask children under the age of 13 to provide more information than is reasonably necessary to provide our services. 

Bentley strongly encourages you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and disclosing personal information online and about using the Internet safely. 

## Use of Cookies

Bentley Web Properties use "cookies" to enable you to sign in to our services and to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies contain information that can later be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. 

Bentley Web Properties use cookies to store your preferences and other information on your computer in order to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalized content and appropriate advertising on your later visits to these sites. 

When you sign in to a site using your credentials, the Bentley Web Properties network stores your unique ID number and the time you signed in to that site in an encrypted cookie on your hard disk. This cookie allows you to move from page to page at the site without having to sign in again on each page. When you sign out, these cookies may be deleted from your computer. Cookies are also used to improve the login experience. For example, your e-mail address may be stored in a cookie that will remain on your computer after you sign out. This cookie allows your e-mail address to be pre-populated so that you will only need to type your password the next time you sign in. If you are using a public computer or do not otherwise want this information to be stored, you can select the appropriate radio button on the login page, and this cookie will not be used. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of Bentley Web Properties and services that depend on cookies. 

## Use of Web Beacons

Bentley Web Property Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons -- sometimes called single-pixel gifs -- that may be used to assist in delivering cookies on our sites and allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. We may include Web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. 

Bentley Web Property pages may also employ Web beacons from third-parties in order to help us compile aggregated statistics and determine the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns. We prohibit Web beacons on our sites from being used by third-parties to collect or access your personal information. 

Finally, we may work with other companies that advertise on Bentley Web Properties to place Web beacons on their sites in order to allow us to develop statistics on how often clicking on an advertisement on a Bentley Web Property results in a purchase or other action on the advertiser's site. 

## Use of Third Party Ad Networks

The majority of the online banner advertisements you see on Bentley Web Property Web pages are displayed by Bentley. However, we allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to display advertisements on Bentley Web Property Web pages. Some of these ad networks may place a persistent cookie on your computer in order to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. Bentley does not have access to nor does it control the cookies that may be placed on your computer by the third-party ad servers or ad networks. 

Bentley maintains relationships with a number of the third-party ad networks currently operating. Those ad networks that use persistent cookies may offer you a way to opt out of ad targeting. You may find more information at the website of either the individual ad network or the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

## Links to Other Sites

Bentley Web Properties may contain links to other sites. Bentley is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites. Please refer to the policies of the respective site. 

## Links to Bentley Web Properties or services

You are welcome to establish a hypertext link to our sites and services as long as the link does not state or imply Bentley's sponsorship of your site. However, you may not use any Bentley logo in conjunction with the link without obtaining Bentley prior express permission to do so. Bentley reserves the right to revoke this courtesy, at its sole discretion. You may not link to our sites or services through a frame. 

## Controlling "Spam" or Unsolicited E-mail

Bentley is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial e-mail, or Spam. Bentley will not sell, lease, or rent its e-mail subscriber lists to third parties. While Bentley continues to actively review and implement new technology, such as expanded filtering features, there is no currently available technology that will totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited e-mail. Using various e-mail client tools and being cautious about the sharing of your e-mail address while online will help reduce the amount of unsolicited e-mail you receive. By using or otherwise accessing Bentley Web Properties, you agree not to gather any e-mail addresses for the purposes of spamming. 

## Intellectual Property

Bentley takes the protection of its intellectual property very seriously. Bentley is a registered trademark and other Bentley product names, service marks, slogans, and logos referenced in Bentley Web Properties are either registered or unregistered trademarks or service marks of Bentley, or one of its direct or indirect wholly-owned subsidiaries. Other brands and product names used in Bentley Web Properties are trademarks of their respective owners. 

Bentley does not review specific requests for guidance concerning the use of trademarks, service marks, logos, or other product names. To the extent a Bentley Web Property does not provide answers to your specific questions, please consult your legal counsel. 

If you have a trademark question pertaining to an existing agreement or other business agreement with Bentley, please contact your Bentley account manager, who will seek advice from Bentley Legal or Bentley Marketing. You may also contact [Bentley Marketing](mailto:http://www.bentley.com/bentleywebsite/tools/sales_contact.aspx). For questions concerning academic use, please contact [becareers@bentley.com](mailto:mailto:becareers@bentley.com). 

Bentley does not advise others on the scope of intellectual property rights. Bentley does not permit or consent to any name, logo, trademark, or service mark to be used that could be confused with or dilute Bentley's trademarks. If you have any questions, you should consult your legal counsel. 

Bentley is committed to respecting the intellectual property rights of others and requests the same of our users. Bentley, in its sole discretion, may terminate the accounts and access rights of users who infringe or otherwise violate others' intellectual property rights. 

## Submissions

Bentley welcomes user input and feedback and provides various services whereby such information can be made available to users of Bentley Web Property services, such as but not limited to FAQs, Tips and Tricks, Case Studies, Examples, Resources, Galleries, and other services. Any user material, information or other communication transmitted or posted to Bentley Web Properties or services, or otherwise provided to Bentley (" **Submission** ") is understood by both parties to be non-confidential and non-proprietary. Bentley has no obligation with respect to any Submission and may freely copy, reproduce, incorporate, distribute, or use such Submission as it wishes. Submissions that are pornographic, violent, obscene, threatening, defamatory, libelous, or violate the law in any way, are prohibited. 

## Miscellaneous

Bentley Web Properties may include inaccuracies or typographical errors. Bentley may make improvements and/or changes in the products, services, programs, and prices described in Bentley Web Properties at any time without notice. Pennsylvania law and controlling U.S. federal law will govern any action arising from use of Bentley Web Properties. 

## Enforcement of This Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should [contact us](mailto:http://www.bentley.com/bentleywebsite/tools/sales_contact.aspx). 

## Changes to This Privacy Statement

We will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our services and user feedback. When we make changes to this statement, the " **Last Revised** " date at the top of this statement will reflect when those changes were made. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Bentley will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Bentley is protecting your information. 

## Contacting Us

Bentley welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please [contact us](mailto:http://www.bentley.com/bentleywebsite/tools/sales_contact.aspx). 

* * *

Bentley Systems, Incorporated, 685 Stockton Drive, Exton, PA 19341-0678.
